<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sophia Aumüller-Wagner</title>
    <description>Website of Sophia Aumüller-Wagner, Diversity Consultant, Project Manager, Workshop Instructor, Sociologist.
</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 21:44:08 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 21:44:08 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>IDCN: Getting internationals into jobs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Bildschirmfoto slim.png&quot; alt=&quot;overview&quot; class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helping Internationals in finding a job is an exciting and challenging task. It means integrating versatile talents into a new job market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my daily work, I get to know professionals from all kind of backgrounds, spanning from highly specialized Microbiologist over experienced Accountants to polyglot Proofreading specialists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined the International Dual Career Network (IDCN) in December 2017 and have been working with membership data management and strategy development. I am in charge of onboarding new volunteers and initiated a project to review membership data in more effective ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I’m designing a strategic approach for a Mentorship Program where the current volunteers will benefit from the expertise of alumni.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IDCN_logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IDCN&quot; class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0 auto&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 16:16:01 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/2018/01/01/IDCN.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2018/01/01/IDCN.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Japan &amp; Racism Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/japan-feature.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;overview&quot; class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August 2016 I had the honor to conduct a workshop at the Idrætshøjskole Bosei situated in Præstø, southern Sjælland. As part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ifas-bosei.renuplus.com&quot;&gt;IFAS&lt;/a&gt; program, 14 Japanese exchange students got hands-on experiences of the concept of a Danish Folkehøjskole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I designed and customized a workshop about racism in Japan and ways to fight it in everyday life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Part 1: “What is racism?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Part 2: “How can we speak up against racism?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;one-half column category&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; src=&quot;/images/DSCF7068-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;one-half column category&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; src=&quot;/images/DSCF7069-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Left: What do you know about racism? - Right: Have you seen or experienced racism before?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my two-part workshop (2x 90 Min), I implemented a broad set of methods ranging from discussions, over a poster making session to a theatre sketch with a racist situation (solution finding). I conducted the workshop in English and had 2 Japanese translators by my side whenever communication was crucial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a main part of the workshop, we watched the movie &lt;strong&gt;Hafu&lt;/strong&gt;, which draws a very intimate picture of what racial discriminations looks like in present-day Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DKp_rYenvGg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;『ハーフ』Hafu - the mixed-race experience in Japan&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most challenging part of the workshop was the actual implementation of our knowledge in everyday life. The participants had a lot of freedom designing their posters and theatre sketch. At the end, we engaged in a concluding discussion about practicability and obstacles of our ideas and strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating these workshops enrichened my perspective a lot and gave me a good skillset of cultural sensitivity across language barriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;one-half column category&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; src=&quot;/images/DSCF7072-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;one-half column category&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; src=&quot;/images/DSCF7074-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, I facilitated a teambuilding workshop together with Danish participants in order to strengthen the bonds of the participants and end our day on a positive and fun note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;one-half column category&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; src=&quot;/images/DSCF6992-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;one-half column category&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; src=&quot;/images/DSCF6996-web.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 17:16:01 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/2016/10/10/Japan-Workshop.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/10/10/Japan-Workshop.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NDC: Educational Workshops for Students</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ndc-pic1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;overview&quot; class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summer 2014, right after I finished my Master studies, I was trained to be a professional workshop instructor. At the Network for Democracy and Courage (NDC) I learned about how to engage participants and present content in an easy-to-understand way. During the workshops, I had to be very flexible and always adapt to the specific needs of the students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By working for the NDC I acquired experiences in:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;development and conduction of workshops (1 to 6 hours long)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;solving arising conflicts, engaging participants, facilitating knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;finding the right approach to a group taking in account age, gender, nationality and social-economic background&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ndc-pic2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pic2&quot; class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NDC is an NGO offering workshops for schools, starting from 5th grade. The workshops are designed to interact with students, discuss current societal problems and empower them to act against discrimination in their everyday lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main focus of the workshops were &lt;strong&gt;racism&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;empowerment&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;diversity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selected workshop topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What does Civil Society mean? How can we participate in democracy?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What does “moral courage” mean and how can we help people being exposed to discrimination?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What is racism and how can we act on it?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;How do gender, sex, and sexuality influence our daily lives?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Right-wing populism and its dangers (e.g. Neo-Nazis or the AfD in Germany)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;one-half column category&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; src=&quot;/images/ndc-pic3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;one-half column category&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; src=&quot;/images/ndc-pic4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The teambuilding exercises were both fun and educational&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teambuilding exercises were one of the most fun parts of my training. Each game or exercise had a specific goal and targeted ‘audience’. In order to correctly assess what your target group needs in the moment, we had to personally instruct and experience the games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the games strengthen the team’s collaboration skills, some are meant to energize you when you’re tired and some are a great method to calm down once things get too heated. And some were just plain fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked for the NDC for more than one year and quit my job at the end of 2015 in order to start my new life in Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/logo-ndc.png&quot; alt=&quot;ndc&quot; class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0 auto&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 16:16:01 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/12/12/NDC.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/12/12/NDC.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
