<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sophia Aumüller-Wagner</title>
    <description>Website of Sophia Aumüller-Wagner, Diversity Consultant, Project Manager, Workshop Instructor, Sociologist.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 14:22:21 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 14:22:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>IDCN: Getting internationals into jobs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Gucke mal da.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 16:16:01 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/01/IDCN.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/01/IDCN.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Japan &amp; Racism Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So einfach geht’s!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 17:16:01 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/10/10/Japan-Workshop.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/10/10/Japan-Workshop.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NDC: Educational Workshops for Students</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/ndc-pic1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;overview&quot; class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summer 2014, right after I finished my Master studies, I was trained to be a professional workshop instructor. At the Network for Democracy and Courage (NDC) I learned about how to engage participants and present content in an easy-to-understand way. During the workshops, I had to be very flexible and always adapt to the specific needs of the students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By working for the NDC I acquired experiences in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;development and conduction of workshops (1 to 6 hours long)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;solving arising conflicts, engaging participants, facilitating knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;finding the right approach to a group taking in account age, gender, nationality and social-economic background&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/ndc-pic2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pic2&quot; class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NDC is an NGO offering workshops for schools, starting from 5th grade. The workshops are designed to interact with students, discuss current societal problems and empower them to act against discrimination in their everyday lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main focus of the workshops were racism, empowerment, and diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selected workshop topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does Civil Society mean? How can we participate in democracy?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does “moral courage” mean and how can we help people being exposed to discrimination?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is racism and how can we act on it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do gender, sex, and sexuality influence our daily lives?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Right-wing populism and its dangers (e.g. Neo-Nazis or the AfD in Germany)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;one-half column category&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/ndc-pic3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;one-half column category&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/ndc-pic4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The teambuilding exercises were both fun and educational&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teambuilding exercises were one of the most fun parts of my training. Each game or exercise had a specific goal and targeted ‘audience’. In order to correctly assess what your target group needs in the moment, we had to personally instruct and experience the games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the games strengthen the team’s collaboration skills, some are meant to energize you when you’re tired and some are a great method to calm down once things get too heated. And some were just plain fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked for the NDC for more than one year and quit my job at the end of 2015 in order to start my new life in Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/logo-ndc.png&quot; alt=&quot;ndc&quot; class=&quot;u-max-full-width&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0 auto&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 16:16:01 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2014/12/12/NDC.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2014/12/12/NDC.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
